Energon signal's gettin' stronger.
能量信号变强了
About five clicks due north.
大概在北方五公里处
What do you mean, speed limit?
你说什么？限速？
I have a gauge in here that goes to 150.
我这里有一档可以开到150码!
If the humans who designed my vehicle form didn't want it to go that fast,
要是设计这车的人类不希望它跑那么快
they shouldn't have given me the option.
那就不该给我装这个档!
Whoa!
哇哦！
Hey, Indy 500!
嘿 飙车少年！
When I'm through with you,
等咱俩完事之后
you're gonna need more than a pit crew to put you back together!
恐怕你要修的就不光是车了
Bring it!
来啊！
Who's the tough guy now, huh?
看看到底谁更经打 嗯？
Hahaha. Relax, Bumblebee.
哈哈哈 别紧张 大黄蜂
I'm just messin' around.
我只不过开个玩笑而已
Found it.
找到了!
Old road rage didn't waste any time posting your mug shots.
愤怒的老司机毫不迟疑地发布了你的照片！
Raf will scrub this as soon as he's back from house hunting.
等拉夫回到家后 他会把这照片擦掉的
Is this what you learned while serving Alpha Trion?!
你跟钛师傅是怎么学的？
I highly doubt that he would have condoned such irresponsible behavior.
我严重怀疑他能否饶恕你这种不负责任的行为!
Blowing your cover is not okay.
不要解除你的伪装!
Sorry, guys. I know I really messed up.
对不起 伙计们 我知道我真的闯了大祸
While Ratchet and Arcee are correct,
救护车和阿尔茜说的都对
I believe that we are all equally responsible for this incident.
不过我觉得这件事我们都有责任
Us?
我们？
How?
怎么可能！
We weren't even there.
我们又不在场！
Well, Bee was.
好吧 小蜂在
Our recent efforts have been so intensely focused on averting crises
我们最近过多地专注于解决危机
that we have overlooked simple matters,
却忽略了一些基础事项
such as teaching Smokescreen how to best function on this planet.
比如 教会烟幕在这个星球上的生存之道
It is an oversight that must be corrected.
我们要弥补这一过失
Optimus, I'm honored to train under you
擎天柱 我很荣幸能接受您的教导
and will do whatever it takes to make things right,
我会不遗余力去弥补过失
to make you proud.
为您争光
Perhaps the best way for you to learn about the human world is from a human.
也许了解人类世界的最好方法 是向人类请教
Smokescreen gets his own partner?
再给烟幕找个搭档？
Please! Isn't having three humans here enough?
拜托 这里的三个人类还嫌不够多吗？
I was referring to one already among us.
我指的是已经和我们在一起的某位
Um... sure, Optimus.
啊… 没问题 擎天柱
don't beat down humans...
不要殴打人类…
I can bring Smokescreen up to speed.
我会让烟幕学好的
We've all put in curbside duty.
我们都经历过学习期
Part of the gig.
这是任务的一部分！
Then let's go for a drive, teach.
那我们上路吧 老师
Optimus, with all due respect,
擎天柱 恕我直言
Agent Fowler is out relocating Raf's family
由于霸天虎发现了拉夫的住址
because the Cons discovered where he lives.
福勒探员正忙着帮拉夫搬家
Meanwhile, Smokescreen, in all his wisdom,
然而烟幕自作聪明选择的汽车形态
chooses a vehicle mode with screaming double "38S" on the doors,
车门上印着一对招摇过市的38
making him an easy target.
很容易被辨识出来
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't more than concerned about Jack's safety.
我没法假装我一点也不担心杰克的安危
Nonetheless,
但是
the fact remains that our new recruit is in need of instruction.
我们的新人的确需要指导
I believe that Smokescreen's spark is in the right place
我相信烟幕有一颗善良的火种
and that he now understands the necessity of protecting humanity.
而且他也已经懂得了必须要保护人类
Okay, intersection. Let's review.
好 到路口了 复习一下
Light's green?
绿灯？
Green for "go".
绿灯行
And yellow?
黄灯？
Go faster!
加速！
Hahahaha. Just messin' around!
哈哈哈 只是开个玩笑
Ha-ha-
哈-哈-
Uh-oh.
啊噢
What is it? Cons?
怎么了？有虎子？
Just someone from school I'd rather not talk to.
只是个学校里我不想见的人
Drive!
开车！
Red light, teach. No can do.
红灯 教练 不能走!
Seriously?
搞什么？
Just... let it go.
算了随他去吧
Are you kiddin' me?
你没开玩笑吧？
Where's your self-respect?
你的自尊呢？
We gotta stand up for ourselves.
我们得为自己出头！
We also have to follow Optimus' rule.
我们还得遵守擎天柱的规定
It's not just about protecting humans...
不光要保护人类
you can't harm them, either.
也不能伤害他们
Who said anything about harming?
我说过要伤害谁吗？
I am so posting this tonight.
今晚我要把这个发出去！
Arcee! Arcee, check out Vince's car!
阿尔茜 阿尔茜 来看看文斯的车！
The bully?
那个小混混
Hey, Vince, did you want fries with that?
嘿 文斯 还想加点薯条吗？
Let me get this straight.
我来把这事捋顺清楚
So you taught Smokescreen everything he never needed to know about fast food.
你教给烟幕的都是些他无论如何也用不上的快餐知识？
He passed drivers ed. Work hard, play hard.
他驾驶考试通过了 寓教于乐
Uh, yeah. No humans were harmed in the making of these photos... honest.
没错 制作这些照片没让任何人类受伤 不骗你！
You have decoded the next Iacon coordinates?
你解密了下一个铁堡坐标？
Excellent, Soundwave!
非常好 声波
Then it is time to beta test our decoy.
这正是测试我们这个诱饵的大好时机…
I am nearly finished decoding the next Iacon coordinates.
我快要解出下一个铁堡坐标了
You may not need to complete your task, Optimus.
你可能没必要继续解了 擎天柱
An Iacon-locator beacon.
铁堡信号？
It seems the Decepticons have already excavated the next relic.
看来霸天虎已经挖出了下一个遗物
Ratchet, triangulate coordinates and activate the ground bridge.
救护车 锁定位置 启动环陆桥
Bring on the Cons!
跟虎子们大干一场！
Where is Smokescreen?
烟幕呢？
Out training again with Jack.
跟杰克在外面“学习”呢
We can not wait.
我们不能等了
Autobots, transform and roll out!
汽车人 变形 出发！
Lord Megatron!
威震天陛下！
I certainly hope that our new acquisition is of Decepticon origin.
要是我们新出土的文物是霸天虎的
It cannot be.
这不可能！
Power of this magnitude
如此强大的力量
must never be allowed to fall into the hands of Optimus Prime...
绝对不能落入擎天柱之手
No matter what.
绝对不行！
Come here!
给我…
The rock is impermeable!
这岩石牢不可破！
The relic is emanating a protective shield!
遗物产生了一种保护层！
It will only respond to the power of a Prime.
只有领袖之力能唤醒它！
We will remove it if we have to take the entire mountain!
要带走它 我们就得移走整座山！
Optimus, I just picked up a second Iacon-locator beacon.
擎天柱 我又发现了另一个铁堡信号！
Optimus, do you read?
擎天柱 听到了吗？
No sign of Cons.
没虎子的踪影！
Oh, dude! My boss is gonna freak!
哦 老兄 我老板要吓死了！
That thing we stuffed in his tailpipe...
我们塞到他排气管里那玩意儿
What's it called again?
叫什么来着？
Pizza!
披萨！
Will you two keep it down?
你们俩能小声点吗？
Arcee? Bulkhead? Can anyone hear me?
阿尔茜？隔板？有谁能听见我说话吗？
Ratchet, what's going on?
救护车 怎么回事？
Our sensors detected a second Iacon-locator beacon,
探测器发现了另一个铁堡信号
but I can't reach Optimus.
但我联系不上擎天柱
I'll go.
我去
Alone?
就你一个？
You have a better option?
你还有更好的选择吗？
He says "fine"...
他虽然答应了
but I don't think he really wants me to go alone.
但看起来他并不想让我只身前往！
I... just pulled a "Miko".
我好像被神子带坏了…
Let's go grab a relic.
有个遗物等着我们去拿！
Whoa! It's a sword!
哇哦 是一把剑！
Not just any sword.
那不是普通的剑
That looks like the Star Saber,
看起来像是星辰剑！
a legendary weapon forged by Solus Prime...
卓天越铸造的神兵利器！
as lore would have it.
这都是…民间传说
It's rumored to wield the power of the Matrix.
传说它能使用领导模块的力量
I'm gonna make Optimus proud.
我要为擎天柱争光
Not a good idea.
那不是个好主意
Why?
为什么？
Because Megatron's here.
因为威震天在这里
The Dark Lord himself.
黑魔王本尊
He won't know what hit him.
他不会想到是谁黑了他！
Smokescreen, wait. Something isn't right.
烟幕 等等 有点不对劲！
Why doesn't Megatron just take the Star Saber?
为什么威震天没有直接拿走星辰剑？
Germaphobe?
他有洁癖？
Seriously, we need to wait for backup.
说真的 我们得等援兵！
You heard Ratchet. Backup's not available right now.
你知道救护车怎么说的 现在援兵来不了
Enough!
好了！
Commence transport!
开始运输！
Who in the pits of Kaon is that?
我的卡隆竞技场啊 那是谁？
Scrap!
见鬼！
It's really in there tight.
插得真紧！
No! No, this can't be happening!
不！不该如此！
Ratchet, you gotta get Optimus here now. Smokescreen went for the relic.
救护车 你得让擎天柱来这儿 烟幕去抢遗物了
I-it's called the "Star Sab..."
叫星辰…
Where in the name of Cybertron are you?
看在塞博特恩的份上 你在哪儿？
And did you say "Star Sabe"?
还有你是不是提到星辰…？
Oh, my...
我的天…
Jack!
杰克！
Optimus, please respond!
擎天柱 请回答！
I can see that you're alive, Optimus.
我知道你们还活着 擎天柱
Why won't you answer me?
为什么不回答我？
Every time we get close to the beacon, the signal moves.
噢 每当我们靠近时 信号就移动了！
All this legwork is giving me itchy fists!
走了这么多脚程 我都手痒了
It seems we have been led astray by a Decepticon trick.
看来我们被霸天虎给耍了
We have a situation.
出状况了！
Bring him to me.
把他带过来！
What is your name, Autobot?
你叫什么 汽车人？
Why? Who wants to know?
怎么？凭什么告诉你？
Where's Optimus?!
擎天柱在哪儿？
Keep Prime from the relic!
别让擎天柱拿到遗物！
I got your back.
有我做你的后盾呢！
Arcee!
阿尔茜！
What could you possible have been thinking?!
你到底在想些什么！
I loosened it for him.
肯定是被我弄松了！
Drop the mountain on him.
把山扔到他头上！
Optimus, retreat!
擎天柱 退后！
Now!
快！
Did he just...
刚才他是不是…？
No way.
不可能！
He can do that?
这都行？
We Decepticons now face our darkest hour.
我们霸天虎…迎来了最黑暗的时刻
How epic was that!!
那简直帅呆了！
I-I saw it with my own optics.
我亲视觉电路所见…
But I still don't believe it.
…仍然难以置信
You know what I don't believe?
知道我最难以置信的是什么吗？
That after everything you've been told,
在反复叮嘱你之后
you still put a human at risk.
你还是令一个人类陷入了危险
A-Arcee, it wasn't his fault. I shouldn't have g...
阿尔茜 那不是他的错 我本该…
Don't you even start with me! We'll talk tomorrow!
别逼老娘发作 明天再跟你算帐
Send Jack home.
送杰克回家！
Green for "go".
绿灯行…
We've been in need of another Autobot in our ranks,
我们的队伍需要的是一个成熟的汽车人
not another child.
而不是小屁孩！
Look, Arcee, I was wrong, and I'm sorry... again.
听着 阿尔茜 我又错了 很抱歉
And if you need to kick me off team Prime...
要是你想把我赶出领袖卫队…
Disregard for human safety... or anyone's safety...
忽视人类的安全 抑或任何人的安全
will not be tolerated. Do you understand?
都不容原谅 你明白了吗？
Fully, sir.
完全明白 长官
We must never lose sight of the fact that upon this Earth,
我们决不能忘记 在这个星球上
we are titans, and such power must be used wisely.
我们是巨人 而这种力量 必须谨慎使用
Whoa!
哇哦！
Optimus, speak to me!
擎天柱 说句话
Optimus!
擎天柱
I am receiving a message.
我收到了一条信息
From who?
谁发来的？
Alpha Trion.
钛师傅…